首先  谢谢两位抽空过来
First off, I want to thank you both for coming.
行了行了  他又做什么了
Yeah, yeah, what'd he do?
他没有做什么啊
Uh, he didn't do anything.
天啊  汤姆  我也想信你这话
Gosh, Tom, I want to believe you.
好吧  问题就是  对谢尔顿来说
Okay, the problem is, the curriculum here
我们的课程不够有挑战性
is not challenging enough for Sheldon.
现在他觉得没意思了
Now, he gets bored
而且或许他没有用最有效的方式
and maybe doesn't express himself
来表达自己的意见
in the most productive way.
所以sin2 + cos = 1
And so the square of sine plus cosine equals one.
谢尔顿
Sheldon.
我不想让您难堪
I don't want to embarrass you,
所以我给您点时间
so I'm going to give you a moment
自己想想您刚才说的话
to think about what you just said.
马克艾罗伊女士
Ms. MacElroy.
怎么了
What?
我很好奇您有没有读过您给我们的指定读物
I'm wondering if you read the book you assigned to us,
因为我读了
because I did.
跑20圈
20 laps.
库珀
Cooper.
如果您要叫我们跑步
If you're going to ask us to run,
您是不是该自己带头以身作则
don't you think you should lead by example?
你的意思是他对老师没礼貌吗
So you're saying he's being rude to his teachers?
这可不行  我们会找他谈谈
That's unacceptable. I'll-I'll give him a talkin' to.
我不知道是不是该说他没礼貌
I don't know if I'd call him rude.
那该怎么说
Well, put a word on it.
没礼貌  就称为没礼貌吧
Rude, let's go with rude.
没礼貌这词就行
Rude is good.
那你想我们怎么做
So what do you want us to do?
我想让你们考虑下给他换种教育方式
I want you to consider another approach to his education.
-好吧  -这是什么意思
- Okay. - What does that mean?
我最近刚好跟
I recently had a nice chat with the head
威尔莫特天才学院的校长谈过
of Wilmot Academy for Gifted Children.
我跟她说了谢尔顿的事  她好像觉得
Now, I told her all about Sheldon, and she seemed to think
谢尔顿非常适合到他们学校就读
he would be a perfect fit over there.
我们已经看过私立学校了
We already looked into private school.
我们承担不起学费
We can't afford it.
-除非你给我加薪  -没这打算
- Not unless you're giving me a raise. - I'm not.
好吧  我就问问
Okay, just checking.
不过我可以告诉你们
But I can tell you this.
众所周知威尔莫特
Wilmot has been known
会为像谢尔顿这样的孩子提供全额奖学金
to give children like Sheldon full scholarship.
你们看看
Take a look at that.
-我的天啊  -真的假的
- My goodness. - No kidding.
你们好好看看
Yeah, just read up on it.
认真考虑一下吧
Give it some thought.
等等
Hold on.
这学校在达拉斯  离这里三小时车程呢
This place is in Dallas; that's three hours away.
是啦  不过...
Well, yeah, but, uh,
像你们这样的案例
what they do in cases like yours,
他们会帮忙找一户当地家庭给他提供寄宿
they look for a local family for him to live with.
乔治  达拉斯呢
And, George, Dallas?
达拉斯的距离够近
Dallas is certainly close enough
他每周末都可以回家过啊
that he can come home on the weekends.
我们很感谢你们为他如此费心
Look, we appreciate you going to bat for him,
但他就是个小孩子
but he's just a wee little thing.
我们怎么能把他送去达拉斯
We can't ship him off to Dallas.
我们不应该先谈过再决定吗
Shouldn't we talk about this first?
有什么好谈的啊  乔治
What's there to talk about, George?
这或许是对谢尔顿很好的机会呢
This could be a great opportunity for Sheldon.
他才9岁
He's nine years old.
那又如何  他又不能用地球年算岁数
Oh, come on, you can't measure him in Earth years.
你在说他是外星人吗
You're saying he's an alien?
我帮乔治说句话
Well, in George's defense,
大家也不是没这么想过...
that idea has been tossed around...
就一两次啦
a little bit.
烂笑话
That's a bad joke.
我能理解这是很大的决定
Look, I understand this is a big decision.
如果你们改变主意了  就打给我
If you change your mind, give me a call.
我很乐意为你们去安排个面试
I'd be more than happy to set up an interview.
-谢了  -不客气
- Uh, yeah. Thank you. - You bet.
谢谢
Thank you.
或许你们才是外星人
Maybe you all are the aliens.
我爱我的工作
I love my job.
♪ 世上没人比我强壮 ♪
♪ Nobody else is stronger than I am ♪
♪ 昨天我移了一座山 ♪
♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain ♪
♪ 我相信我能当你的英雄 ♪
♪ I bet I could be your hero ♪
♪ 我是个了不起的小家伙 ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man ♪
少
年
谢尔顿
我不知道你们怎么舍得拒绝不去
Well, I don't understand how you could turn this down.
那学校看起来很赞啊
This place looks fantastic.
在320公里外呢  妈
It's 200 miles away, Mom.
我知道达拉斯在哪里
I know where Dallas is.
我以前都去那里买大麻
I used to buy my marijuana there.
真的吗
Really?
我说了"以前"
I said "used to"
然后我怀上了这货
Then I got pregnant with this one
然后乐子就离我一去不复返
and all the fun stopped.
我的意思只是
All I am saying is that
这或许对谢尔顿是很好的机会
this would be a great opportunity for Sheldon.
我知道你说得有道理
I know, you're right.
她说得对吗
Whoa, she's right?
我今天在办公室里也说了同样的话
I said the same thing in Petersen's office,
你就像看傻子一样看我
you looked at me like I was an idiot.
就是这表情
Yeah, that's the look.
或许你们在这事上都有些自私了
Maybe y'all are being a little selfish about this.
自私吗  我们是为他着想
Selfish? We're thinking of him.
这样是很不错啊
Well, that's all well and good,
但或许你们该为全世界也想想
but maybe you should be thinking about the whole world.
我的意思是
I mean,
要是爱因斯坦的父母也阻止他的发展呢
what if Einstein's parents had held him back?
那我们就不会有...
We wouldn't even have the...
本来要说原子弹
Well, I was gonna say atomic bomb,
但应该有别的更好的例子
but there's probably a better example.
我有个疯狂的建议
Here's a crazy idea:
要不我们问问谢尔顿自己的看法呢
how about we ask Sheldon what he thinks of all this?
问吧  但他不会想去的
Go ahead, but he's not gonna want to go.
这里是他的家  我们是他的家人
This is his home, we're his family.
谢尔顿  你能过来一下吗
Sheldon, can you come in here for a minute?!
怎么了
Yes?
-过来坐  我们想跟你说件事  -好吧
- Have a seat. We want to talk to you. - All right.
今天我们知道在达拉斯有家学校
So, today we found out about a school in Dallas
是为特别聪明的孩子开设的
for really smart kids.
我什么时候能去就读
When can I start?
等等  达拉斯很远
Hold on. Dallas is far away,
你去了就得住在别人家
so you'd have to live with another family.
他们有养狗吗
Do they have a dog?
我们不知道
Uh, we don't know.
那你能打电话问问吗
Well, can you make some calls?
可以吧  但是你不会想爸爸妈妈吗
I guess, but wouldn't you miss your mom and dad?
或许会吧
Yes, I suppose I will.
所以你什么时候能打去问狗的事
So, when are you calling about the dog?
你真是了解他呀
You know him so well.
他们是什么毛病
What's wrong with them?
你是什么意思
What are you talking about?
他们好安静
They're so quiet.
他们是吃了药吗
Are they on medication?
不是  他们只是跟你一样聪明
No, they're just smart like you.
原来我以前是在动物园里上学啊
I've been going to school in a zoo.
这制服我有点说不准啊
Not sure about these uniforms.
感觉有点娘
Kinda froufrou.
弗罗拉·道格拉斯博士
谢尔顿  我看了你的成绩单
Sheldon, I've been looking over your transcripts
不得不说  非常出色啊
and I must say, I am very impressed.
谢谢
Thank you.
您的博士学位是哪方面的
What's your doctorate in?
非交换代数拓扑
Noncommutative Algebraic Topology.
我喜欢她
I like her.
谢尔顿不在这里会感觉很奇怪吧
It's gonna be weird around here without Sheldon.
应该是变不奇怪才对吧
Don't you mean less weird?
这么说太不友好了
That's not nice.
我没有想要友好啊
I wasn't trying for nice.
你确定你不是在嫉妒
You sure you're not jealous
你弟弟更上层楼了吗
'cause your little brother's moving up in the world?
我对自己的人生也有计划
Hey, I got plans of my own.
-愿闻其详  -等到我高中毕业
- Do tell. - Soon as I graduate high school,
我就要去当一个职业男模
I'm gonna be a professional male model.
真是笑死人了
That is hilarious.
怎么  我长得很帅啊
What? I'm good-lookin'.
不是  是你觉得你高中能毕业
No, that you think you'll graduate high school.
模特的部分也很好笑
The model thing was funny, too.
不得不说
I must tell you,
我在这里任职多年  但从没见过
in all the years I've been here, I have never seen
老师们集体写出如此高评价的推荐函
such glowing letters of recommendation from a student's teachers.
-那真是太好了  -你们听听
- Well, that's real nice to hear. - Now, listen to this:
"除了他超凡的智商
"Putting aside his superior intellect,
谢尔顿还是课堂上的一个宝
Sheldon is a delight to have in the class.
他风趣爱笑
He's fun-loving,
平易近人
Easy to get along with,
还总是乐于助人"
and always ready to help another student."
这听起来完全不像我啊
That doesn't sound like me at all.
当然像啦  宝贝
Sure it does, sweetie.
道格拉斯博士
Dr. Douglas...
别  叫我弗罗拉就可以了
Oh, no. Please call me Flora.
弗罗拉  我必须得跟您请教关于住的事情
Flora, I have to ask about the living arrangements.
那是我们最关心的事
That's our main concern.
这件事你们可以放一百个心
Well, I think I can reassure you about that.
我跟我丈夫一直给一名学生
My husband and I have been hosting a student
提供寄宿了许多年  他最近刚毕业
for the last several years who recently graduated
现在去名校普林斯顿大学了
and is now at Princeton.
所以我们家现在有多一间空的客房
So we have a guest room available in our home.
您真是太慷慨了
That's very generous of you.
您丈夫也在学校里教书吗
Does your husband work at the school also?
没有  他退休了
No, he's retired.
他以前是太空总署的天体物理学家
He was an astrophysicist for NASA.
请告诉我你们家没养狗
Please tell me you don't have a dog.
没养  我们夫妇对狗过敏
No. We're both allergic.
我心痒难耐
I'm tingling.
姥姥
Meemaw?
Meemaw.
我知道  我特别好看
I know. I look great.
我有离别礼物要送你
I got you a little going away gift.
进来
Come on in.
这项链在我们家族传了许多代了
This necklace has been in our family for generations.
曾是一个科曼奇族勇士的所有物
It belonged to a Comanche warrior
他把它送给了你曾曾曾曾祖母
who gave it to your great-great-great-great grandma.
他为什么要给她
Why'd he give it to her?
根据我们的家族传说
Well, according to family lore,
她是个非常"好客"的姑娘
she was, uh, a very accommodating young lady
他们一拍即合
and, uh, they hit it off.
这是鸟羽
That's a bird feather.
-是鹰羽  -都无所谓
- Eagle feather. - Doesn't matter.
我不喜欢鸟  鸟都很脏
I don't like birds; birds are filthy.
别说了
Okay.
行吧
Fine.
一个无羽的传家宝
One featherless family heirloom
让你带着上路  保你平平安安
for you to take with you and keep you safe while you're away.
你不会真相信这东西有魔力吧
You don't actually believe this has magic powers, do you?
我的神啊  你就说"谢谢"就行了
Oh, for God's sake, just say "thank you."
谢谢
Thank you.
上面有标价
There's a price tag on it.
并没有
No, there's not.
我来啦
Hello!
有人在家吗
Anybody home?
你来啦
Hi.
玛丽
Mary.
他每周五晚上都会回来
He's gonna come home every Friday night.
我一直以为得等到他上大学
I didn't think I'd have to deal with this
我才会需要面对这种事
till he went to college.
你就谢谢上天保佑
You should thank your lucky stars
他不是现在在上大学吧
he's not in college now.
我还是不确定这个决定对不对
I'm still not sure that this is the right thing to do.
你是担心他不喜欢那里
Are you worried that he won't like it
还是担心他会喜欢上呢
or are you worried that he will?
你这是帮倒忙
You're not helping.
安慰你不是我的职责
That's not my job.
我自认为是实话发表员
I think of myself as a speaker of truth.
如果你不打算安慰我  就走吧
If you're not gonna make me feel better, go away.
真不好意思  你甩不掉我了
I'm sorry. You are stuck with me.
如你们所见
As you can see,
即使在我小的时候
even as a small child,
大家就喜爱我的陪伴
people cherished having me around
会为我的离开而哭泣
and wept over my absence.
对我即将离开  没人比我最好的朋友丹
And no one took my impending departure harder
更难过了
than my best friend, Tam.
你明天就走了吗
So you leave tomorrow?
是的
Yes.
达拉斯
Dallas.
没错
Yes.
真棒
Cool.
我很感动
It was touching
看着丹勇敢地忍住眼泪
to watch Tam bravely fight back tears.
你有没有考虑过让火车朝顺时针方向走
Have you ever thought about making the trains go clockwise?
没有
No.
你应该考虑一下
You should.
勇敢  非常勇敢的丹
Brave, brave Tam.
你醒着吗
You awake?
是的
Yes.
你会想我吗
Are you gonna miss me?
我还没想过这件事
I haven't given it any thought.
我们躺着也没事干
Well, we're just lying here.
现在想想吧
Think about it.
我习惯了有你在
I am used to you.
我也习惯了有你在
I'm used to you, too.
这跟喜欢你不是一回事
It's not the same as liking you.
确实不是
No.
对我来说  你就像豆角
To me, you're like string beans.
没人主动想要
No one asks for them,
没人质疑它们的存在
no one wonders about them.
它们就出现在盘子上
They're just there on the plate.
但你会吃掉  对吧
But you eat them, right?
是的
Yes.
你会想我的
You're gonna miss me.
好了  我们来做饭前祷告
All right, let's say grace.
看来现在轮到我跟你握手了
Guess I get to hold hands with you now.
看来是的
Guess so.
也许谢尔顿戴手套也不是个坏主意
Maybe Sheldon's mittens weren't such a bad idea.
感谢上帝  赐予我们食物
Thank you, God, for this food we are about
给予我们身体营养
to receive and for the nourishment of our bodies.
请保佑为我们准备食物的人
And bless the hands that prepared it.
还有  上帝  请你照看我们的谢尔顿
And, God, we ask that you watch over our Sheldon...
因为他开启了一段精彩的新...
as he begins this wonderful new...
因为他开启了
...as he begins
人生一段精彩的新篇章
this wonderful new chapter in his life.
-阿门  -阿门
- Amen. - Amen.
你为什么哭了
Why you cryin'?
你为什么那么蠢
Why you stupid?
今天在达拉斯情况怎么样
So how'd it go in Dallas today?
挺顺利的
Went fine.
他们都很友善
Nice people.
感觉谢尔顿对一切都感到挺自在的
Sheldon seemed very comfortable with the whole thing.
欢迎  一路上顺利吗
Welcome! How was the drive?
进城时有点堵车  但除此以外都很顺畅
Eh, a little traffic comin' into the city but otherwise okay.
谢尔顿  来见见我丈夫  艾略特
Sheldon, I want you to meet my husband, Elliot.
艾略特  这是谢尔顿
Elliot, this is Sheldon.
认识你很高兴  小伙子
Well, it's nice to meet you, young man.
我听说了很多关于你的事
I've heard a lot about you.
乔治  他们根本不是这个样子
George, that is not at all how they were.
你在说什么呢
What are you talking about?
他们绝对有些不对劲
There was definitely something off about those people.
真的吗
Really?
我错过什么了
What'd I miss?
欢迎
Welcome!
一路上顺利吗
How was the drive?
进城时有点堵车  但除此以外都很顺畅
Eh, a little traffic comin' into the city but otherwise okay.
谢尔顿
Sheldon,
谢尔顿  来见见我丈夫  艾略特
I want you to meet my husband, Elliot.
艾略特  这是谢尔顿
Elliot, this is Sheldon.
认识你很高兴  小伙子
Nice to meet you, young man.
我听说了很多关于你的事
I've heard a lot about you.
拜托
Oh, come on.
你说得他们好像是怪物一样
You're making it out like they were some kind of monsters.
谢尔顿有自己的房间
Sheldon has his own room.
到处都摆满了书
There's books everywhere.
还有个很大的后院  虽然他不会去玩
Even has a big old backyard he won't play in.
你是不是忘了什么
Aren't you forgetting somethin'?
什么
What?
地下实验室
The underground laboratory.
我想那叫装修过的地下室  亲爱的
I think it's called a finished basement, honey.
我知道自己看到了什么
I know what I saw.
玛丽  今天很累了
Mary, it's been a long day.
我们能不能就安静吃饭
Can we just have a quiet dinner?
好啊
Sure.
"他们都很友善"
"Nice people."
那我们为什么还把他留在那里
Then why did we leave him there?
因为我们爱他  希望给他最好的
Because we love him and we want the best for him.
气氛好紧张
This is tense.
我和孩子们今天过得很愉快
Me and the kids had a nice day.
看了很多橄榄球赛
Watched a lot of football.
话说  迈阿密海豚队的头盔上真有只海豚
You know, the Dolphins' helmet has a dolphin on it.
那只海豚也戴了一顶头盔
And that dolphin is also wearing a helmet.
但这顶头盔上就没有海豚图案了
But his helmet doesn't have a dolphin on it--
而是印着"M"
it has the letter "M."
我们聊这个话题聊了一小时
We talked about that for an hour.
好了
All right.
开动吧
Dig in.
不好意思
Excuse me.
我们不做饭前祷告吗
Aren't we going to say grace?
我们家不做这个
Uh, we don't do that in our house.
但你想做可以做
But you're welcome to do so.
没关系  我不信有上帝
That's all right. I don't believe in God.
那你为什么要做饭前祷告
Well, then why would you say grace?
因为那会让我妈妈高兴
Because it makes my mom happy.
那你为什么戴着手套
And why are you wearing mittens?
因为我不知道你们的手都摸过什么
Well, I don't know where your hands have been.
好吧
Okay.
不如我们开始吃吧
Maybe we should just eat.
你喜欢豆角吗
Do you like string beans?
不喜欢
No.
但我会吃掉
But I eat them.
谢尔顿  能听到吗
Sheldon, can you hear me?
我是你的双胞胎姐姐  米希
It's your twin sister, Missy.
家里一切都好
Everything's all right here,
但我觉得妈妈超想念你
but I think Mom misses you real bad.
好吧  我听不见你的声音
All right, I can't hear you,
我要挂断了
so I'm gonna hang up now.
晚安
Good night.
我告诉你  这是个坏主意
I'm telling you, this is a terrible idea.
是个糟透了的坏主意
This is a terrible, terrible idea.
他不会有事的  你等着瞧
He's gonna be fine. You'll see.
真不敢相信你对此没意见
I can't believe you're okay with this.
我当然有意见
I'm not okay with this.
我只是为了你  努力坚强
I'm just trying to be strong for you!
什么  你之前觉得他离开是个好主意
What? You thought him leaving was a good idea.
我那么说只是因为你觉得那是个坏主意
Oh, I only said that because you thought it was a bad idea.
你也知道跟别人唱反调是我的天性
You know how it's always my nature to go the other way.
说"上"
Say "up."
上
Up.
下
Down.
我出去一趟
I'll see you in a bit.
你要去哪儿
Where are you off to?
我要去达拉斯接谢尔顿回来
I'm going to Dallas to get Sheldon.
-当真吗  -当真
- Really? - Yeah, really.
之前说的这对他是个好机会呢
What about this being a great opportunity for him?
你们到底想不想我去
Y'all want me to go or not?
-想  快去  -想啊  赶紧的
- Yes! Go! - Yes, and hurry up!
快点  小胖仔
Get a move on, Tubby.
你要去哪儿
Where you going?
去接谢尔顿
To get Sheldon.
这事我有表决权吗
Do I get a vote in this?
没有
No.
靠
Dang.
那晚我无法轻易入睡
Sleep didn't come easy that night,
因为我知道
knowing that, at any moment,
我随时可能会被斩首
I could be decapitated.
还嫌那情况不够糟似的
And as if that wasn't bad enough,
我房间的床有防尘罩
the bed in my room had a dust ruffle,
在我幼小的头脑里  这只意味着一件事
which, to my young mind, only meant one thing:
这里有尘
there was dust.
但最终我还是迷迷糊糊睡着了
But, eventually, I did drift off,
心神不宁
haunted by the memory,
脑海里回放着我们三人围在钢琴旁
the three of us gathered around the piano
唱嬉皮民歌的画面
singing hippie folk music.
♪ 你不会看到没啥能比过伟大奎恩的事物 ♪
♪ You will not see nothin' like the mighty Quinn♪
Mighty Quinn - Manfred Mann
来  现在一起唱
Come on. Sing along now.
♪  快来啊 ♪
♪  Come all without ♪
♪  都快来啊 ♪
♪  Come all within ♪
♪ 你不会看到没啥能比过伟大奎恩的事物 ♪
♪  You will not see nothin' like the mighty Quinn. ♪
"你不会看到没啥"
"You'll not see nothin'"
不管是谁写的  都丢死人了
Shame on whoever wrote that.
原作者是诺贝尔文学奖的主鲍勃·迪伦
爸爸
Dad?
什么事
Yeah?
你来接我  我很高兴
I'm glad you came to get me.
我也是
Me, too.
♪ ...能比过伟大奎恩的事物 ♪
♪  ...nothing like the mighty Quinn ♪
不要
No!
你收到我的信息了
You got my message!
不要抱抱  不要抱抱
No hugging! No hugging!
我何苦努力当上老师
I mean, why'd I bother becoming a teacher?
他在我开口前  就知道我要说什么
He knows what I'm gonna say before I say it.
或者我说完后看起来宛如智障
Or I say it and look like a dumbbell.
英格拉姆女士  我能提个建议吗
Ms. Ingram, can I offer a suggestion?
什么
What?
-没事了  你按你方式来吧  -不  不
- Never mind. You do it your way. - No, no.
你告诉我  告诉我错哪儿了
You tell me. Tell me how I'm wrong.
你多假设了一个欧几里德几何的公理
You assumed an extra axiom of Euclidean geometry
但你没有定义它
without stating it.
他说得对吗
Was he right?
当然对了
Course he's right.
他每次都对
He's always right.
告诉你我怎么做
Tell you what I do.
我让他去跑腿
I send him on little errands.
比如前几天  我叫他
Like the other day, I told him,
"去材料房帮我拿砝码斯坦"
"Go to the supply room and get me a framastan."
砝码斯坦是什么
What's a framastan?
没这玩意  我编的
No such thing. I made it up.
整堂课他都没回来
He was gone the whole period!
太有才了
That's genius.
我要借用这一招
I'm using that.
但别用"砝码斯坦"  这是我的词
Don't use framastan. That's mine.
这里是什么情况
What's going on here?
你说过他要转学的
You said he was going away.
骗子
Liar.
才早上11点你们就开始喝酒了吗
It's 11:00 in the morning, guys.